more and get with some agents on our
players and and again help uh kick off
this 2026 season. So, time's yours.
>> Yeah, I mean, we've had a lot of
dialogue with uh with Trent uh last
spring, last summer, and um you know,
he's first out of the gate, I think,
tomorrow. So, looking forward to get
with him, and obviously Trent's a great
player and see what we can do there. But
certainly love to have Trent back and uh
for the long term.
It's [clears throat] funny, you know,
every year when we were picking 31, 32,
I'd always say, "Man, if we were just at
24 or 25, we'd be exactly where we want
to be." And now we're at nine. I'm like,
"Man, if we were just at four or five,
we'd be exactly where we want to be."
So, I think every GM kind of has that
mindset where, you know, unless you have
the first pick, uh, there's a certain
element that you can't control and you
have to let the dominoes fall, if you
will. But, you know, we're excited. I
mean, we don't want to be picking nine
every year, but we're excited to um add
some young talent to this roster. And I
think even more excitingly, those
second, third rounds where felt like
years past, day one would end, we'd come
in there and there'd be five or six
players, but you knew at 32 in round
two, you wouldn't get them either. So,
it's not just the first round. I think
we have an opportunity to really
capitalize here and and add a lot of
talent throughout the course of uh the
draft weekend.
Yeah, I think we've kind of taken a
different approach uh with Travis in the
sense that I think, you know, we've kind
of prepared for either scenario and
coach had mentioned on Friday, he's had
great dialogue with Travis on our end,
myself, Chris Shay, Travis's crew. We've
had some good dialogue there. Um and I'm
sure we're going to see him here just
like we will um all the other players
agents and and we'll continue that
dialogue. But um Travis is the best.
He's an icon and hopefully he comes back
and we'll just kind of let that process
play out.
>> Oh, well, I think it's it's it's a
combination of all those. I mean, it's
it's it's not your typical, hey, 27y old
first time at free agency. I mean,
Travis has done everything. He's
accomplished everything. He's about to
get married. He's got a lot going on.
And so I don't think there's an element
of us not trying to um you know, you
need some sort of deadline timeline, but
at the same time, I mean, it's Travis
Kelce, so we're going to just continue
to have positive dialogue and and see
where this thing ends. But I think we're
trying to position ourselves that either
either way, you know, we have a plan
moving forward. as far as construction.
[snorts]
>> Well, I think it's certainly we want to
get more explosive in the running game
and you know we we've invested in that
interior and um you know with Trey Smith
and Creed Humphrey I mean two of the
best in the league and we thought
Kingsley made a big step. I I mean that
those are three talented interior
players. So I think and we've talked
about it and coach has done an amazing
job with his staff cranking on that
scheme val. But I think being more
explosive in the running game and really
taking advantage of those interior three
to kind of uh impose your will on an
opposing team's defense. But I mean the
running game takes a lot of pressure off
everybody. So I think if we can be more
explosive and more effective in the
running game, I think obviously we take
a lot of pressure off Pat, especially
coming back early in the season with the
injury.
Um, so everything's
>> kind of a puzzle and it I I think with a
lot of our players, I don't think that
there's any one of our free agents that
we look and say we don't want these guys
back. I mean, they're really good
players. We won a lot of games with
them. It's just a matter of trying to
put the puzzle together and what else is
going to be out there, their price
points, and kind of fitting the whole
thing together. So, I think what we do
is we just kind of um remain in contact
and and keep that dialogue open, but all
those players that you'd mention or if I
didn't mention any of the um the Chanels
and the Cooks and um the Watsons, I
mean, all these guys were monitoring and
we're trying to get as many back as we
can. Obviously, it's unrealistic to
think you will. Um but we have to be
able to go in different directions. I
mean, there's sometimes where you don't
think a guy's going to come back here
and then all of a sudden because you
either didn't execute something or
someone else took a different deal,
things open back up. And so, I think you
just need uh need to remain flexible and
and uh and fluid during these
situations. But always have, you know,
layers of uh backup plans when you enter
this, you know, part of the season.
Um, well, I think it's on on the the
rise to a degree, but um, typically
the better you are and the more higher
profile you are, I mean, it's the less
leverage you have sometimes and you
know, and then those players follow suit
with other players and everyone kind of
does the same thing. So, I think it's
always been the case where it kind of
varies um when you get to the degree of
of each and every player, but um that's
a good question. I don't know to what
percent is it on the rise. Um I know
it's it's something that all teams
utilize and and we do as well and a lot
of it comes down to just kind of the
caliber of player or the tier of player.
>> We're doing it when we can. Um, I mean
that's just one of those things we do
and you know, especially with the guys
that have a little bit more injury
history and I mean there has to be a
trade-off too if you're going to give
some guy a contract and you know there
there is a bit of that injury question
and so I think we always try to
implement that but you know I think it
varies by by player and position.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah. I mean, you see it when you look
at when we go through these prospects
and we're looking at the tags and you
see their birth dates and then you look
at your roster and a lot of the guys are
just as as young as these guys, right?
And so, and then it kind of trickles
down. I think you also see it too. I
think [clears throat] when the official
um decision date for these underassman
came out, I believe we moved over 25
guys off our board that we had top 75,
top 100. So, it really impacts I think
the draft and and then you're getting
older older prospects as you go on. So,
I don't think that's going to change
anytime soon and that's something that
we have to adapt to. uh until there's
some wholesale changes on what they do
on the college side. Um I think this is
just going to be the way it the way
things work now and it's for us to adapt
and adjust to it and position yourself
to get some of the younger players that
have a little bit more growth and um you
know
>> typically the second and third round
would be those guys that maybe they
didn't play a lot but they were young.
Well now these guys are just bouncing
and getting paid by another school and
paying so and getting paid and playing.
So it's it's a little bit
that two, three, four round where you
got these younger developmental guys
that haven't scratched the surface yet.
You're getting a little bit more already
finished product and um so that's
challenging but I think it's again what
we have to adapt to and that's goes into
how you position your board and you know
when to be aggressive and when not to be
aggressive.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, and listen, part of
the process is to just find guys that
love to play and love the process. And,
you know, I mean, if you're drafting
guys, too, they're your goal is to
ultimately pay them and have them still
come back with the same desire and
hunger like the Mahomes and the Creeds
and the Trees. And so, um, yeah, I don't
think I've seen a dip off in that. I do
see just a talent pull shrinking.
>> [snorts]
>> Um, so
>> with Jawan, um, Mike Dana was a little
unique and different. Mike D was in the
building this week. I had a chance to
talk to Mike and and you guys know Mike.
I mean, he is as good as it gets. Um,
just a tremendous player and person and
have a lot of respect for him and wanted
to just have that opportunity since I
saw him this weekend to just let him go
out there and and see what his market is
and and we'll remain in contact. And I
think with, you know, with guys like
Dwan and and and Drew Tranwell, someone
asked me about earlier. Um, you know,
these guys started for us and they play
a lot of football for us and again,
our cap situation, I don't know if we're
six or seven over, but I think we have
60 million in convertible contracts,
too. So, I mean, we have many different
ways um to attack this. And I think
that's the one thing that we've been
good at. We don't do a lot of money
pushed out in the future years. And I
think we run a pretty tight ship there.
So, this gives us flexibility to do
different things. So again, that's part
of the process with all those guys and
we'll see how the how the um you know
scenario shake out.
Well, I mean that's [clears throat]
that's a better question for Andy. Um,
but the one thing that
Andy takes a lot of pride and joy in, I
think, is we always talk about the coach
and all the accomplishments on the
field, but Andy's one of those guys that
really finds value in the day-to-day
interactions with his staff and with his
coaches, and he uses every moment as a
teachable moment. And so obviously his
kids are involved. Um his family's
close. They're all part of it. Um but
that work life balance. I think that
work life balance, the work is done in
the facility, but also the life balance
is done in the facility with the way he
mentors everyone, the coaches, the
players, um his family's a part of it.
So um just a unique individual. You
don't run into people like that very
often that their work becomes them but
they give so much on and off the field.
>> A couple more here guys. Couple more.
>> What's that?
>> Well, I mean the I mean talking football
and and you know
every position group is different,
right? And so and I'm sure most GMs
would tell you that and most coaching
staffs will tell you that.
um there are certain positions that um
how they process information and and now
look this is only 20 minutes so we're
not going to like throw a kid up there
or kill a kid but it's a start and then
you have your informal time here you
have potentially formal time here you
have Zoom opportunities now and then you
have in-house 30 visits and our coach
can go visit them so I think sometimes
when there's a question I don't think
anything's determined here I think it's
part of the process and So, um, you
know, we've had a couple guys yesterday
that, you know, just some of the
football knowledge stuff we weren't sure
on and they, I mean, they kind of nailed
it and we were really impressed and, um,
only 20 minutes on, you know, on the
other side there. We're going to make
sure that that is what it is. But, um,
our college scouts do a great job of
paying the pitcher and having me, uh,
the coaching staff, everyone in that
room prep for here, you know, here's the
player and here's here's the background
situation, here's where he's from, and,
you know, here are the things. You know,
some of these guys are smart. They just
don't articulate it well. Um, so it's
just seeing the whole piece puzzle piece
come together. And um I like I said, I I
don't think we um take a bunch of names
off, but it it's just a pathway to to
keep digging and and getting as much
information as possible.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, I mean it's it's a great question
and I mean I think there's the old
school I mean you're always going to O
line Dline. Um
those positional values are there. You
see them in free agency. Uh, but at the
same time, I mean,
arguably some of the best players in
this draft are maybe at non premium
positions when you look at, you know,
the Ohio State linebacker, the Notre
Dame running back, the safety at Ohio
State. So, those are really, really good
players. It's hard to find faults with
their tape are really solid. Um, but
again, some of those more premium
positions, interior D line, edge
rushers, um, you know, they're hard to
find. And then with those guys, the
problem with those guys is they're hard
to find and then they don't really
become available in free agency. Some of
those other positions, they're good
players. You'll probably eventually get
a chance to get some of those positions
from free agency. So that's kind of the
things you just have to weigh, you know,
um kind of go through and weigh out all
the options. But at the end of the day,
I think you just want a guy that's going
to come in here and and be a great
contributor on the field, off the field,
and um stick to that old old mantra.
Take the best player available, right?
>> [snorts]
>> I think every year I I mean it's a
challenge and uh you know we do have
some flexibility with how we're set up
to to do some different things but you
it's not like we have 90 million in cap
space and um we know we have to execute
an efficient game plan and for agency
and then we got to got to nail these
picks and that'll be important for us to
keep you know this um this run going.
Obviously, we had a step back last year
and everyone's disappointed and um but
everyone's motivated and um you know,
even the coaching staff, too, with like
I said, the last few years, we hadn't
had a chance to really get with them
much before the combine and um right
after that Vegas game, I mean, those
guys were all in and it was exciting and
um and energetic in a way just to get
out there. And I think the last few
years, you know, we were kind of just
like in a maintenance stage and now
we're trying to just rebuild this thing
again. And I think for um a GM and a
personnel staff, that's exciting.
>> Yep. Thank you guys.